So three people were arrested
for interfering with the police.
（ｷｬｽﾀｰ）
公務執行妨害で３名を逮捕しました
一連の
雛見沢(ひなみざわ)ダム建設反対を巡る運動は
The actions against
the Hinamizawa Dam...
...have elevated since last month's
bloody clash with the riot squad.
先月の機動隊との流血事件を…
- Bye-bye. L- See you.
...have elevated since last month's
bloody clash with the riot squad.
（寿樹(としき)）バイバ～イ
（男の子）じゃあね
警察では
過激な活動家による次の事件を…
The police are on close watch
for future extremist problems.
Cabinet Minister Inukai was
directly appealed to last week.
（役所の男）君 犬飼(いぬかい)寿樹君？
Cabinet Minister Inukai was
directly appealed to last week.
Are you Toshiki Inukai?
Toshiki Inukai
- "Time Wasting" Chapter -
Episode 01: HINAMIZAWA
When They Cry
Furimuita sono ushiro no
(shoumen dare)?
Kurayami ni tsume wo tatete
(yoru wo hikisaita).
Amadare wa chi no shizuku to
natte nodo wo tsutai ochiru.
Mou dokonimo kaeru
basho ga nai nara...
...kono yubi tomare
watashi no yubi ni.
Sono yubi goto tsuretette ageru.
Higurashi ga naku
akazu no mori e.
Atomodori wa mou dekinai.
（赤坂(あかさか)）私は赤坂衛(まもる)
I am Mamoru Akasaka.
私が あの少女と出会ったのは
ある誘拐事件が きっかけだった
I met that young girl due
to one kidnapping case.
（室長）推定48時間前
建設大臣の孫に当たる―
About 48 hours ago, a Ministry
of Construction official's son...
建設省幹部の子息が
誘拐されたもようです
...the cabinet minister's
grandson, was kidnapped.
It's believed to settle
this matter peacefully...
（室長）建設大臣は
事態を穏便に済ませるため―
...the minister won't report it
and will comply with demands.
警察へ通報せず
要求に応じるものと思われます
（室長）
大臣宅の通話を監視した結果
After monitoring
the minister's phone...
...we've confirmed suspicious
calls from outside the city...
都外からと思われる不審な電話が
確認され
事件発生は間違いないものと
断定しました
...and a crime
has indeed occurred.
That's all. Please proceed
with the utmost secrecy.
（室長）
以上 極秘に捜査を進めてください
（室長）赤坂君
（赤坂）あっ…
Akasaka-kun.
君は大臣に陳情してきた―
Go investigate the anti-dam
group that petitioned the minister.
雛見沢ダム建設反対の団体を
調査してくれ
Yes, sir.
（赤坂）はい
こんな田舎の住民団体の仕業とは
到底 思えないが―
It's hard to believe this was done
by a group of rural citizens...
Mainichi Times
Protest Against Dam Expands
It's hard to believe this was done
by a group of rural citizens...
Mainichi Times
Protest Against Dam Expands
...but we must
eliminate all possibilities.
全ての可能性を
つぶしていかなくてはならない
分かりました
Understood.
（室長）直接 現地へ行って
県警で情報を取ってくれ
Go straight there and
canvass the local police.
（赤坂）はい
Yes, sir.
（赤坂）すまない　下手をすると
出産日までに戻れないかもしれない
I'm sorry.
Worst case, I may not
come back for the delivery.
（雪絵(ゆきえ)）フフッ… いいんです
心配しないで行ってきて
It's okay.
Please don't worry and go.
I'll be waiting for
you with this baby.
（雪絵）
待ってますから この子と一緒に
“鬼ヶ淵(おにがふち)死守同盟”か…
Onigafuchi Final
Defense Alliance, huh...
Normally, a rookie like me
doesn't investigate alone.
本来 私のような駆け出しが １人で
捜査に当たることは まずない
But because
we're short-handed...
…が
人手が足りなかったことに加え―
その団体が この誘拐事件の
核心から程遠い存在であると―
...and this group was judged to
be far removed from this case...
判断した上層部の
異例の配置であった
...the higher-ups gave
me this unusual role.
（本田屋(ほんだや)）やあ どうもどうも
Well, hello, hello.
（本田屋）
遠路はるばる お疲れさまでした
Thanks for coming
all the way here.
I apologize for suddenly
visiting during your busy time.
ご多忙中 突然 おジャマして
申し訳ありません
警視庁から来た赤坂と申します
よろしくお願いします
I'm Mamoru Akasaka of the
national police. Nice to meet you.
（本田屋）公安部の本田屋です
I'm Hondaya from public safety.
Anti-gang chief Sankai browbeat
me not to resist your assistance.
“県警暴対”の山海(さんかい)部長から―
協力を惜しむなと
脅されとりますので
“暴対”？
県警の暴力団対策本部ですか？
Anti-gang? The prefecture
police's anti-gang department?
ウチじゃ 鬼ヶ淵死守の連中は―
The Onigafuchi Final Defense
Alliance is organized crime to us.
暴力団の延長に
位置づけてますんでねえ
あれを善意の住民運動だなんて
とんでもない
It's unbelievable to call that
a good-willed citizens' movement.
Oh? Just when I wondered
what you're talking about...
（大石(おおいし)）おや？
何の話をしているかと思えば…
Oh, Kura-chan. Nice timing.
（本田屋）
おお 蔵(くら)ちゃん ちょうど良かった
はるばる東京の警視庁から
お見えになった赤坂さん
This is Akasaka-san, all the way
from Tokyo's national police.
Let me introduce you to
Oishi-kun from investigations.
ご紹介します
こちら 刑事部の大石君
赤坂さんがお問い合わせの
鬼ヶ淵の連中のことなら―
He's familiar with the Onigafuchi
people you're asking about.
彼が詳しいです
ハハハッ… なんでしたら
村を実際に ご案内しましょうか？
If you'd like, shall I give
you a tour of the town?
よろしくお願いします
Yes, please.
（赤坂）
大石氏は雛見沢のことに関して―
Oishi explained many
things about Hinamizawa.
いろいろと説明してくれた
No dam! Don't build the dam!
Leave! You'll pay! Nature killers!
Like its three great families.
雛見沢の御三家のこと
その御三家の中でも―
No dam! Don't build the dam!
Leave! You'll pay! Nature killers!
And how among them, the
Sonozakis have absolute power.
園崎(そのざき)家の力は
絶対的なものであること
Sonozaki
Their head, Oryou Sonozaki, is
basically Hinamizawa's leader...
その当主 園崎お魎(りょう)が
雛見沢の実質的なリーダーであり
Sonozaki
...who also leads
the anti-dam movement.
ダム反対運動も お魎が指揮を執り
活動は年々
エスカレートしていることなどを…
Sonozaki
Their activities are
escalating every year.
You came all the way from
Tokyo to investigate, right?
あなた 東京から はるばる
調べにいらしたんですよねえ
えっ？ ええ そうですが
（大石）あっ じゃ あれだ
Yes, that's right.
Oh, then this involves the direct
appeal to Minister Inukai?
あの犬飼大臣への
直訴事件の絡みですかな？
That means
the Public Safety Department...
（大石）要するに
要注意団体ってことで―
公安が ここを
マークすることになった …と？
...decided to investigate here
to keep an eye on the group?
That you know why
makes things easier.
お察しが早くて助かります
ウソでしょう？
（赤坂）えっ…
You're kidding, right?
だから―
You're kidding that they're
marked due to the appeal, right?
直訴事件でマークが
ついたっての ウソでしょう？
フフフッ… あなたって人は
ホントに隠し事が下手なんですねえ
You're horrible
at keeping secrets, huh?
I actually like your
innocence and candidness.
そういう素直で初々しいの
悪くないなぁ
I thought I may be more helpful
to you if you told me the truth.
本当のところを教えてくれりゃ―
もっと お力になれると
思ったんですがねえ
How would you be helpful?
（赤坂）どう力になれるんです？
I could introduce you to people
who know a lot about them.
（大石）連中に詳しい情報屋に
引き合わせてもいいですよ
協力員ですか？
（大石）はい
A spy?
Yes.
どうして私の任務に興味を？
（大石）そりゃ あなた…
Why are you interested
in my mission?
Well, it's like
a give-and-take situation.
持ちつ持たれつってやつですよ
フフフフッ…
（赤坂）はい
Yes.
~Hinamizawa Village~ See
splendid nature! People needed.
I see.
（赤坂）えっ そうですか…
次回の募集はないんですか
~Hinamizawa Village~ See
splendid nature! People needed.
No future opportunities...
（公由(きみよし)）あんた 雑誌の人か何か？
（赤坂）いえ 個人です
Are you here for
a magazine or something?
No, for personal reasons.
Personal? For sightseeing?
個人？ 観光ですかね？
（赤坂）はい
Yes, I read in a magazine that
some precious nature is around.
雑誌で とても貴重な自然が
残ってると読んだもので
ハハハハッ…
なら あんた 来なさい 来なさい
Then you should come!
村は ちょっと慌ただしいけど
歓迎しますよ
The village is a bit hectic,
but we welcome you.
Please let me do so. Thank you.
是非 そうさせていただきます
ありがとうございます
はい… ええ
Yes. Yes.
Exit
かわいい
Cute.
（梨花(りか)）ウ… ウ～ン…
Mi.
Mi?
Mi...
M-Mi...
ああっ…
怪しい者(もん)じゃないんだ 私は！
I'm not anyone strange.
にぱ～！
N-paa.
N-N-paa...
に… にぱ～…
When They Cry
（牧野(まきの)）どうも 本日は…
Well, hello!
あっ 遅れて申し訳ないこってす
I'm sorry for being late.
昨日 お電話くださった
観光の方ですかねえ？
You're the sightseer
who called yesterday, right?
あ～… はい
Oh, yes.
Don't stand there. Please get on.
（牧野）
すったらんと お乗りください
天気も また崩れそうだから
ちゃきちゃき ご案内しますよ
The weather looks like it'll get
bad again, so I'll give a quick tour.
あっ はい
- Okay.
- Mi.
Hey, it's Rika-chan!
（牧野）あっれ～？
梨花ちゃまでねえですか
ありがたや ありがたや
What a blessing,
what a blessing.
にぱ～！
N-paa.
牧野は
これから お仕事なのですか？
Makino, do you have work now?
She calls him just "Makino"?
“牧野”って… 呼び捨てか？
村長に
村さ 観光してえ若者さ来るから
The village headman
asked me to show around...
...a young fellow who's coming
to sightsee various places.
いろいろ案内してやってけれって
頼まれまして
Are you the young fellow
who's sightseeing the village?
村を観光したい若者なのですか？
（赤坂）あっ まあね
Yes.
この村の自然が
とても貴重だと聞いたんで―
I heard the nature
here is quite precious...
是非 カメラに収めたいと
思ったんだよ
...so I thought I'd love
to take some pictures.
富竹(とみたけ)２号なのです
You're Tomitake #2.
えっ 富竹？
Tomitake?
にぱ～！ ハハッ…
（赤坂）あっ…
N-paa.
こんなのが面白いのですか？
（赤坂）いや…
This is interesting to you?
Well, I felt the kind of nostalgic
feel it has gives a nice touch.
どことなくノスタルジックな
雰囲気が渋いかな …なんて
Is Hinamizawa fun?
雛見沢は楽しいですか？
（赤坂）うん 楽しいよ
Yes, it is fun.
退院したら 是非 家内を連れて
もう一度 来たい
Once my wife's out of
the hospital, I want to come back.
With my newborn baby along.
そのときは
生まれている子供も一緒にね
Well then, let me take you to the
place with the best view last.
うんじゃ 最後に―
いちばん景色のいい所さ
案内しましょうかね
いちばん景色のいい所ですか？
The place with the best view?
（牧野）そりゃ もちろん
境内からの景色さ置いて―
Why, of course.
No other place can compare
with the view from there.
ほかにありやしやせんかねえ
That means I can
invite you to my home.
では 赤坂を
ボクのお家(うち)へ ご招待なのです
えっ？ 梨花ちゃんのお家って？
Your home?
神社ですよ 古手(ふるで)神社
It's the shrine, Furude Shrine.
高台にありましてね
いい景色さ見られるんですよ
It's on high grounds, so you
can get a great view from there.
Furude Shrine?
古手神社…
Rika Furude.
（赤坂）古手梨花…
One of the three great families...
御三家の子だったのか
にぱ～！
N-paa!
これは…
This is...
No dam! Oyashiro-sama
curses you! We'll never approve!
This is...
（牧野）神社はダム反対運動の
事務所も兼ねてましてね
No dam! Oyashiro-sama
curses you! We'll never approve!
This shrine is also the anti-dam
movement's main office.
いやぁ こんな風景も あんたらにゃ
安保闘争みてえで懐かしいでしょう
But this is like the fight against
the Japan-US Security Treaty.
私は別に活動家ではありませんので
I'm actually not an activist, so...
国の政策に暴力や立てこもりで
対抗しようというのには―
Fighting national policy with
violence and locking selves in...
私は同意できません
I can't agree with that.
ほう…
あんた 立派な意見さ お持ちだねえ
I see that you have a fine opinion.
政策に意見したかったら
同じ意見の政治家に投票するか
If you want a say, vote for
a politician with the same views...
...or jump into the world of
politics and debate your point.
自ら政治の世界に飛び込み―
意見を主張するべきであると
思っています
That's the bedrock
of democracy.
それが民主政治の原点
赤坂が何を言ってるのか
全然 分からないのですよ
I don't understand
anything you're saying.
ごめんね
梨花ちゃんには難しい話だったね
Sorry, it was
a difficult subject for you.
Japan is a peaceful country...
（赤坂）日本は平和の国だから―
...so if you have something to say,
you have to do it peacefully.
自分の言いたいことは 平和的に
訴えなきゃいけないということさ
では 赤坂
Then, Akasaka...
この村は どうやったら
ダムに沈まなくなるのですか？
...what can this village do to not
be submerged by the dam?
We can only live here.
（梨花）ボクたちは
ここでしか生きていけないのです
都会では生きていけないのです
We can't live in the city.
Makino-san, is that the
sightseer who called yesterday?
（公由）牧野さん
その人？ 電話くれた観光の人は
そんです
こちら 雛見沢の公由村長さん
Yes. This is Hinamizawa's
village headman, Kimiyoshi.
Kiichirou Kimiyoshi, huh...
公由喜一郎(きいちろう)か…
（公由）ようこそ 雛見沢へ
Welcome to Hinamizawa.
いかがでしたか？
静かで ゆっくりした所でしょう
How was it?
Isn't it a quiet and calm place?
Y-Yes, I enjoyed visiting many
beautiful places the entire day.
今日１日 美しい場所を
いくつも堪能させていただきました
へえ また紳士な方だねえ
Well well, what a gentleman.
Akasaka, over here.
Hurry, hurry!
（梨花）
赤坂 こっち！ 早く早くなのです！
（赤坂）ああ それじゃ すいません
（公由）ハハッ…
Well then, excuse me.
（赤坂）これは… すごい！
This is amazing.
This is my favorite place.
（梨花）ボクの いちばんの
お気に入りの場所なのですよ
I can't believe such a beautiful
village will be under a lake...
こんな美しい村が
湖底に沈むことになるなんて…
信じられないよ
（梨花）沈みませんよ
It's not going to sink. The dam
plan will definitely go away.
ダム計画なんて
必ず なくなっちゃいますのです
…だといいね
I hope so.
Akasaka, do you believe
this village will sink?
赤坂は この村が沈んでしまうと
思っていますか？
沈んでほしくはないよ けど…
I don't want it to sink, but...
It won't because the dam plan
is going to be gone soon.
沈みませんよ
ダムの計画は
もうすぐ なくなりますですから
“なくなる”？
- Gone?
- Yes, it will be gone.
はい なくなりますのですよ
どうして そう言い切れるんだい？
How can you be so sure?
Regardless of what you do,
the dam plan will end this year.
（梨花）
赤坂が何をしても しなくても―
ダム計画は
今年で終わりになってしまうのです
It's already been decided.
もう決まっていることなのですよ
なんで そう思うんだい？
Why do you think so?
It's already been decided.
決まっていることなのです
ほかに言いようがないのですよ
There's no other way to put it.
えっ？
き… 決まっているっていったって
Even if you say
it's been decided...
あっ 危ないよ 梨花ちゃん！
That's dangerous, Rika-chan!
（梨花）赤坂
（赤坂）あっ…
Akasaka.
Go back to Tokyo.
東京へ帰れ
It's best to go
back to Tokyo quickly.
（梨花）あなたは
さっさと東京に帰ったほうがいい
Otherwise,
you'll regret it very much.
でないと
ひどく後悔することになる
（赤坂）後悔？
Regret?
I have warned you.
警告はした　あとは あなたしだい
The rest is up to you.
き… 君は誰だ？
梨花ちゃんじゃない…
Who are you?
You're not Rika-chan...
誰なんだ？
Who are you?
（赤坂）ハッ… 梨花ちゃん！
Rika-chan!
Rika-chan... Rika-chan!
梨花ちゃん… 梨花ちゃん！
ウ～ン…
Rika-chan...
梨花ちゃん…
Mi.
Mi!
Then I'll leave
the rest to Sato-san.
じゃ
あとはサトさんに任せますから
Oishi-san, you're leaving?
大石さんは帰られるんですか？
私が一緒でも
おジャマしちゃうだけでしょう
I'll just be in the way if I stay.
Besides, you're the one
who offered Sato-san the job.
それに サトさんの仕事を
買ったのは あなたですから
Well, let's go.
（ｻﾄ）じゃ 行こうか
（ｻﾄ）
旦那から 雛見沢村については―
You've heard about
Hinamizawa from him, right?
多少のことは聞いてるんだろう？
はい 大体は
Yes, pretty much.
なら 前置きは なしでいこう
（赤坂）お願いします
Then let's get to it.
Please.
The Sonozakis had
a family meeting last night.
（ｻﾄ）ゆうべ
園崎家で親族会議が開かれた
（赤坂）親族会議？
Family meeting?
中心人物は園崎家当主 お魎
At the center was the Sonozaki
family head, Oryou Sonozaki...
...her granddaughter, Mion,
who's said to be the heir...
（ｻﾄ）
その跡継ぎといわれてる孫娘の魅音(みおん)
...and the leaders
of the other great families.
更に その脇には 残りの御三家
古手家 公由家の重鎮たち
The Furude and
Kimiyoshi families.
In addition, there were
several direct relatives.
そのほかにも
直系の親族が あと何人か
What was discussed
at that meeting?
（赤坂）その会議で―
一体 何が話されたんですか？
ダムの反対運動がらみの話だが―
Mainly stuff concerning
the anti-dam movement...
問題は その会議の最後に出た話だ
...but the issue is what
was discussed at the end.
The end?
最後？
I see. It was a tough one.
（お魎）そう
難儀なこともあったものよのぅ
What's the matter, Oryou-san?
どうしたんだい？ お魎さん
If for us, the land is our mother...
我らにとって 土地が母なら―
...then the dam is a disturbance
that threatens our mother's life.
ダム建設は
母の命を脅かされる―
騒ぎっちゅうこったろうなぁ
I heard the grandson of the dam's
minister has been kidnapped...
（お魎）ダムの親玉の大臣がのぅ
孫さらわれちまって
右往左往しとるっちゅう話だ
...and that it's causing chaos.
We're even.
これで おあいこだのぅ
That can't be.
バカな…
犬飼大臣の孫が誘拐された話は
どこにも漏れていないはずだ
The kidnapping of Minister Inukai's
grandson shouldn't be public.
それをどうして知っている？
How do they know?
Oryou-san, is that true?
お魎さん そりゃ本当かい？
我らの痛みは母を失う痛みじゃのぅ
Our pain is the pain
of losing our mother.
I don't think it's
completely similar...
それに値するとは思わんが
...but he certainly deserves
the pain of losing a grandchild.
孫を失う痛み… 少しは
こたえるといいんじゃがのぅ
（お魎）だが 土地と
人さまの子では ワケが違うのぅ
But there's a difference between
the land and someone's child.
I don't mind the kidnapping,
but I don't want him to be injured.
隠すのは かまわんが
ケガだけは
させたくないものよのぅ
子にゃ 何の罪もねえ
大事にしたれな
The child is innocent.
Take care of him.
それは つまり 鬼ヶ淵死守同盟が
誘拐事件に関与しているということ
So the Onigafuchi
Final Defense Alliance...
...was involved in the kidnapping?
We can't be completely certain.
（ｻﾄ）
必ずしも そうとは言えねえな
しかし 当主であるお魎が―
But the head, Oryou...
...gave orders on how to treat
the kidnapped grandchild.
誘拐した孫の処遇について
指示を出しているということは…
We can't tell
whether her words...
（ｻﾄ）その言葉が指示なのか―
それとも
単なる お魎の独り言なのか
...were an order or
just her personal thoughts.
それは分からない
That's all Oryou said regarding
the kidnapped grandchild.
孫の誘拐について
お魎が述べたのは ここまでだ
I hope you found some things
you were concerned about.
あんたの知りたかったことが
含まれてりゃいいんだが
Buddy, I don't know what
kind of work you do...
（ｻﾄ）にいさん
何の仕事やってるか知らんけど
...but if you're facing the Sonozaki
family, you'd better be prepared.
園崎家を相手にすんなら
相当の覚悟でやっとけよ
（ｻﾄ）
大石の旦那も２～３回 襲われてる
Oishi's been attacked
two or three times.
He wore a knifeproof vest even
on his days off, though not lately.
最近は着てねえけど―
一時は オフのときも
防刃ベストを着込んでた
A knifeproof vest?
防刃ベスト？
You ever been in the national
police's public safety unit?
にいさん ひょっとして 警視庁の
公安部の人ってことはある？
えっ？ まさか ハハハッ…
No way...
ハハッ… こっからは
サービスってことで話してやるよ
Then I'll tell you
this out of courtesy...
After the kidnapping case,
another case came up.
誘拐の話が出たあと
もうひとつの話題が出たんだ
何ですか？
What?
To investigate
the grandchild's kidnapping...
大臣の孫さらったのを
調べるために―
...it's been said Tokyo's public
safety sent an investigator.
東京から公安の捜査官が
派遣されてくるっちゅう話だ
A public safety investigator?
（公由）公安の捜査官？
大臣の孫の誘拐な
For the minister's grandchild.
They can't blow it
out of proportion...
うかつにゃ
大事(おおごと)にできゃんってことで―
...so public safety is said to be
investigating it on their own.
警視庁の公安部が
独自で調べとるっちゅう話だ
They're making such a fuss.
大仰なこったのぅ
うん？ どうした？
What's wrong?
Did the national police come?
警視庁が来たのですか？
おお おお… 梨花ちゃまは
警視庁も知ってなさるんかい
Oh, Rika-chan knows what
the national police is, eh?
偉いのぅ
Good girl.
Who came?
誰が来たのですか？
公安の どんなヤツが来よったんか
誰ぞ 分かるヤツは おらんかいな？
Does anyone know what kind of
person came from public safety?
A newbie is what I heard.
（魅音の父親）新米の若造が１人と
聞き及んでおりますが
A newbie? Is he freshly new?
新米？ ホカホカなのですか？
（父親）ええ 新米とか
Yes, a newbie.
A young, fresh newbie.
ホカホカのフッカフカ～！
（父親）
ええ ホッカホカのフッカフカ
Yes, he's young and fresh.
What should we do, Mother?
どうしますか？ お義母(かあ)さん
（お魎）放っといたれな
Leave it alone.
But if he causes too much harm,
then don't hesitate at that point.
まあ あんまり
おいたが過ぎるようやったん―
そんときゃ 遠慮せんでな
ナメられるのは好っきやせんね
I don't like people fooling with me.
（梨花）
ホッカホカのフッカフカ～！
A young, fresh newbie.
（ｻﾄ）まあ
俺の知ってるのは そのぐらいだ
Well, that's all I know.
Just be careful.
せいぜい気をつけるんだな
（赤坂）ウ～ン…
はい…
（大石）赤坂さんですか？
- Yes?
- Is this Akasaka-san?
Good morning. This is Oishi.
おはようございます 大石です
フフフッ…
アア… どうも
Oh, hello.
Did you just wake up?
ひょっとして 今お目覚めですか？
ハハハハッ… あなたの眠気を―
I have a story that may
completely wake you up.
覚ましてあげられるかも
しれない話があります
Yes?
雛見沢駐在所から届いた遺失物に
興味深い物が交じっていたんです
Something interesting was sent
to a station's lost and found.
遺失物？
Lost and found?
財布ですか？
A wallet?
Look at this.
（大石）見てください
Medical Examination Card
Toshiki Inukai
And...
（大石）それと…
Medical Examination Card
Toshiki Inukai
This was found in Takatsudo,
which is a ghost town.
あるのは廃村です
なんとも寂しい所ですからねえ
It's such a lonely area.
Oishi-san, could you
take me to Takatsudo?
大石さん 高津戸へ
案内してもらうことはできますか？
Sure, no problem.
（大石）ええ かまいませんよ
What are you doing?
何をしてるんですか？
A precaution.
用心ですよ
If you're taking risks,
you'd better be properly prepared.
火中の栗(くり)を拾うなら
相応の用意が必要と思いましてねえ
あなたも着ます？
Will you wear one too?
To get my happiness,
I had done everything...
...but had done nothing
to be blamed and accused of.
The sound of footsteps
became louder every day.
Then I noticed the fact
there was no time.
I was a believer in life,
to be myself always.
And was asking
whether I would be alive.
Give me a reason
why not to adopt in this way.
Or judge me to be guilty
of so many incurable sins.
Tell me why or why not?
Complaining way too much.
Maybe I overlooked
something fatal for me.
Preview
What is being sought
is the unwavering image.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
求めているのは 揺れない面影
What is being searched for
is the lit escape route.
探しているのは 光の抜け道
与えられたのは いつもの悲しみ
What has been provided
is the usual sadness.
「ひぐらしのなく頃に」
When They Cry.
"Time Wasting" Chapter,
Episode 2: SIGN.
- "Time Wasting" Chapter -
Episode 02: SIGN
"Time Wasting" Chapter,
Episode 2: SIGN.
あなたは信じられますか？
- "Time Wasting" Chapter -
Episode 02: SIGN
Can you believe it?